<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2014//EN" "http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/corehtml/query/DTD/pubmed_140101.dtd">
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">32990929</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2020</Year>
            <Month>12</Month>
            <Day>17</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-7365</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>36</Volume>
                    <Issue>1</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2021</Year>
                        <Month>Jan</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Metabolic brain disease</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Metab Brain Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Linking chronic kidney disease and Parkinson's disease: a literature review.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>1-12</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11011-020-00623-1</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) has been typically implicated in cardiovascular risk, considering the function the kidney has related to blood pressure, vitamin D, red blood cell metabolism, and electrolyte and acid-base regulation. However, neurological consequences are also attributed to this disease. Among these, recent large epidemiological studies have demonstrated an increased risk for Parkinson's disease (PD) in patients with CKD. Multiple studies have evaluated individually the association of blood pressure, vitamin D, and red blood cell dysmetabolism with PD, however, no study has reviewed the potential mechanisms related to these components in context of CKD and PD. In this review, we explored the association of CKD and PD and linked the components of the former to propose potential pathways explaining a future increased risk for PD, where renin-angiotensin system, oxidative stress, and inflammation have a main role. Potential preventive and therapeutic interventions based on these associations are also explored. More preclinical studies are needed to confirm the potential link of CKD conditions and future PD risk, whereas more interventional studies targeting this association are warranted to confirm their potential benefit in PD.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Meléndez-Flores</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jesús D</ForeName>
                    <Initials>JD</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Neurology Division, Internal Medicine Department, University Hospital &quot;Dr. José E. González&quot;, Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Madero y Gonzalitos S/N, 64700, Monterrey, NL, Mexico.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Monterrey, Mexico.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Estrada-Bellmann</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Ingrid</ForeName>
                    <Initials>I</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-7812-0462</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Neurology Division, Internal Medicine Department, University Hospital &quot;Dr. José E. González&quot;, Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Madero y Gonzalitos S/N, 64700, Monterrey, NL, Mexico. ingridestmann@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Movement Disorders Clinic, Neurology Division, Internal Medicine Department, University Hospital &quot;Dr. José E. González&quot;, Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Monterrey, Mexico. ingridestmann@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>09</Month>
                <Day>29</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Metab Brain Dis</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>8610370</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0885-7490</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anemia</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic kidney disease</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative stress</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson’s disease</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renin-angiotensin system</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>07</Month>
                <Day>07</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>09</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>30</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>30</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>9</Month>
                <Day>29</Day>
                <Hour>12</Hour>
                <Minute>38</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32990929</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11011-020-00623-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11011-020-00623-1</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
        <ReferenceList>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Agarwal R, Nissenson AR, Batlle D, Coyne DW, Trout JR, Warnock DG (2003) Prevalence, treatment, and control of hypertension in chronic hemodialysis patients in the United States. Am J Med 115:291–297</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12967694</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Annuk M, Fellström B, Akerblom O et al (2001) Oxidative stress markers in pre-uremic patients. Clin Nephrol 56(4):308–314</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11680661</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Arnold R, Issar T, Krishnan AV, Pussell BA (2016) Neurological complications in chronic kidney disease. JRSM Cardiovasc Dis 5:2048004016677687</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27867500</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5102165</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Asahina M, Vichayanrat E, Low DA et al (2013) Autonomic dysfunction in parkinsonian disorders: assessment and pathophysiology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 84(6):674–680</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22942216</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Ashby DR, Gale DP, Busbridge M, Murphy KG, Duncan ND, Cairns TD, Taube DH, Bloom SR, Tam FWK, Chapman RS, Maxwell PH, Choi P (2009) Plasma hepcidin levels are elevated but responsive to erythropoietin therapy in renal disease. Kidney Int 75(9):976–981</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19212416</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Attia AH, Gadelkarim M et al (2017) Meta-analysis of Creatine for Neuroprotection against Parkinson's disease. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets 16(2):169–175</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27823574</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Babitt JL, Lin HY (2012) Mechanisms of anemia in CKD. J Am Soc Nephrol 23(10):1631–1634</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22935483</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3458456</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Benigni A, Cassis P, Remuzzi G (2010) Angiotensin II revisited: new roles in inflammation, immunology and aging. EMBO Mol Med 2(7):247–257</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20597104</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3377325</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Bhan I, Burnett-Bowie SA, Ye J et al (2010) Clinical measures identify vitamin D deficiency in dialysis. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 5:460–467</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20185603</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2827576</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Biancardi VC, Son SJ, Ahmadi S, Filosa JA, Stern JE (2014) Circulating angiotensin II gains access to the hypothalamus and brain stem during hypertension via breakdown of the blood-brain barrier. Hypertension 63:572–579</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24343120</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Biancardi VC, Stern JE (2016) Compromised blood-brain barrier permeability: novel mechanism by which circulating angiotensin II signals to sympathoexcitatory centres during hypertension. J Physiol 594:1591–1600</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26580484</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Bitner A, Zalewski P, Klawe JJ, Newton JL (2015) Drug interactions in Parkinson's disease: safety of pharmacotherapy for arterial hypertension. Drugs Real World Outcomes 2(1):1–12</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27747611</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4883207</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Blesa J, Przedborski S (2014) Parkinson's disease: animal models and dopaminergic cell vulnerability. Front Neuroanat 8:155</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25565980</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4266040</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Blesa J, Trigo-Damas I, Quiroga-Varela A, Jackson-Lewis VR (2015) Oxidative stress and Parkinson's disease. Front Neuroanat 9:91</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26217195</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4495335</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Borazan A, Ustün H, Ustundag Y, Aydemir S, Bayraktaroglu T, Sert M, Yilmaz A (2004) The effects of peritoneal dialysis and hemodialysis on serum tumor necrosis factoralpha, interleukin-6, interleukin-10 and C-reactive-protein levels. Mediat Inflamm 13:201–204</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Cabantchik ZI, Munnich A, Youdim MB, Devos D (2013) Regional siderosis: a new challenge for iron chelation therapy. Front Pharmacol 4:167</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24427136</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3875873</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Calvello R, Cianciulli A, Nicolardi G, de Nuccio F, Giannotti L, Salvatore R, Porro C, Trotta T, Panaro MA, Lofrumento DD (2017) Vitamin D treatment attenuates neuroinflammation and dopaminergic neurodegeneration in an animal model of Parkinson's disease, shifting M1 to M2 microglia responses. J NeuroImmune Pharmacol 12:327–339</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27987058</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Cao W, Li A, Wang L, Zhou Z, Su Z, Bin W, Wilcox CS, Hou FF (2015) A salt-induced Reno-cerebral reflex activates renin-angiotensin systems and promotes CKD progression. J Am Soc Nephrol 26(7):1619–1633</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25635129</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4483588</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Caravaca-Fontan F, Gonzales-Candia B, Luna E, Caravaca F (2016) Relative importance of the determinants of serum levels of 25-hydroxy vitamin D in patients with chronic kidney disease. Nefrologia 36:510–516</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27378232</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Chen H, O'Reilly EJ, Schwarzschild MA, Ascherio A (2008) Peripheral inflammatory biomarkers and risk of Parkinson's disease. Am J Epidemiol 167(1):90–95</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890755</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Chen J, Zhang C, Wu Y, Zhang D (2019) Association between hypertension and the risk of Parkinson’s disease: a meta-analysis of analytical studies. Neuroepidemiology 52:181–192</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30726850</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Cristol JP, Canaud B, Rabesandratana H et al (1994) Enhancement of reactive oxygen species production and cell surface markers expression due to haemodialysis. Nephrol Dial Transplant 9(4):389–394</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8084452</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Członkowska A, Kohutnicka M, Kurkowska-Jastrzebska I, Członkowski A (1996) Microglial reaction in MPTP (1-methyl-4-phenyl-1,2,3,6-tetrahydropyridine) induced Parkinson's disease mice model. Neurodegeneration 5(2):137–143</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8819134</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>de Lau LM, Breteler MB (2006) Epidemiology of Parkinson’s disease. Lancet Neurol 5(6):525–535</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16713924</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Deckers K, Camerino I, van Boxtel MP et al (2017) Dementia risk in renal dysfunction: a systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective studies. Neurology 88(2):198–208</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27974647</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5224710</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Deng Q, Zhou X, Chen J, Pan M, Gao H, Zhou J, Wang D, Chen Q, Zhang X, Wang Q, Xu Y (2017) Lower hemoglobin levels in patients with parkinson's disease are associated with disease severity and iron metabolism. Brain Res 1655:145–151</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27840188</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Dhaun N, Goddard J, Webb DJ (2006) The endothelin system and its antagonism in chronic kidney disease. J Am Soc Nephrol 17:943–955</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16540557</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Dhondup T, Qian Q (2017) Electrolyte and Acid-Base disorders in chronic kidney disease and end-stage kidney failure. Blood Purif 43(1–3):179–188</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28114143</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Dounousi E, Papavasiliou E, Makedou A, Ioannou K, Katopodis KP, Tselepis A, Siamopoulos KC, Tsakiris D (2006) Oxidative stress is progressively enhanced with advancing stages of CKD. Am J Kidney Dis 48(5):752–760</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17059994</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Duni A, Liakopoulos V, Roumeliotis S et al (2019) Oxidative stress in the pathogenesis and evolution of chronic kidney disease: untangling Ariadne's thread. Int J Mol Sci 20(15):3711</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6695865</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Dusso AS (2011) Kidney disease and vitamin D levels: 25-hydroxyvitamin D, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D, and VDR activation. Kidney Int Suppl 1(4):136–141</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Ehrenreich H, Aust C, Krampe H, Jahn H, Jacob S, Herrmann M, Sirén AL (2004) Erythropoietin: novel approaches to neuroprotection in human brain disease. Metab Brain Dis 19(3–4):195–206</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15554415</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Erbaş O, Çınar BP, Solmaz V, Çavuşoğlu T, Ateş U (2015) The neuroprotective effect of erythropoietin on experimental Parkinson model in rats. Neuropeptides 49:1–5</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25464888</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Etgen T, Chonchol M, Förstl H, Sander D (2012) Chronic kidney disease and cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Nephrol 35:474–482</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22555151</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Etminan M, Gill SS, Samii A (2005) Intake of vitamin E, vitamin C, and carotenoids and the risk of Parkinson's disease: a meta-analysis. Lancet Neurol 4(6):362–365</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15907740</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Evatt M, DeLong M, Kumari M, Auinger P, McDermott M, Tangpricha V, Parkinson Study Group DATATOP Investigators (2011) High prevalence of hypovitaminosis D status in patients with early Parkinson disease. Arch Neurol 68:314–319</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21403017</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Eyles DW, Smith S, Kinobe R, Hewison M, McGrath JJ (2005) Distribution of the vitamin D receptor and 1 alpha-hydroxylase in human brain. J Chem Neuroanat 29(1):21–30</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15589699</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Fishbane S, Pollack S, Feldman HI, Joffe MM (2009) Iron indices in chronic kidney disease in the National Health and nutritional examination survey 1988-2004. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 4(1):57–61</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18987297</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2615715</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Floyd RA (1999) Antioxidants, oxidative stress, and degenerative neurological disorders. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med 222(3):236–245</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601882</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Galvan DL, Green NH, Danesh FR (2017) The hallmarks of mitochondrial dysfunction in chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 92(5):1051–1057</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28893420</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5667560</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Goddard J, Johnston NR, Hand MF, Cumming AD, Rabelink TJ, Rankin AJ, Webb DJ (2004) Endothelin-a receptor antagonism reduces blood pressure and increases renal blood flow in hypertensive patients with chronic renal failure: a comparison of selective and combined endothelin receptor blockade. Circulation 109:1186–1193</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14981006</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>González EA, Sachdeva A, Oliver DA, Martin KJ (2004) Vitamin D insufficiency and deficiency in chronic kidney disease: a single center observational study. Am J Nephrol 24:503–510</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15452403</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Granata S, Zaza G, Simone S, Villani G, Latorre D, Pontrelli P, Carella M, Schena F, Grandaliano G, Pertosa G (2009) Mitochondrial dysregulation and oxidative stress in patients with chronic kidney disease. BMC Genomics 10:388</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19698090</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2737002</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Greenamyre JT, Cannon JR, Drolet R, Mastroberardino PG (2010) Lessons from the rotenone model of Parkinson's disease. Trends Pharmacol Sci 31(4):141–143</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20096940</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2846992</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Greenberg SM, Vernooij MW, Cordonnier C, Viswanathan A, al-Shahi Salman R, Warach S, Launer LJ, van Buchem M, Breteler MM, Microbleed Study Group (2009) Cerebral microbleeds: a guide to detection and interpretation. Lancet Neurol 8(2):165–174</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19161908</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3414436</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Grolez G, Moreau C, Sablonnière B, Garçon G, Devedjian JC, Meguig S, Gelé P, Delmaire C, Bordet R, Defebvre L, Cabantchik IZ, Devos D (2015) Ceruloplasmin activity and iron chelation treatment of patients with Parkinson's disease. BMC Neurol 15:74</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943368</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4429376</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Gyurászová M, Gurecká R, Bábíčková J, Tóthová Ľ (2020) Oxidative stress in the pathophysiology of kidney disease: implications for noninvasive monitoring and identification of biomarkers. Oxidative Med Cell Longev 2020:1–11</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Hall CN, Klein-Flügge MC, Howarth C, Attwell D (2012) Oxidative phosphorylation, not glycolysis, powers presynaptic and postsynaptic mechanisms underlying brain information processing. J Neurosci 32(26):8940–8951</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745494</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3390246</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Hall JE (2003) The kidney, hypertension, and obesity. Hypertension. 41:625–633</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12623970</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Hiller AL, Murchison CF, Lobb BM et al (2018) A randomized, controlled pilot study of the effects of vitamin D supplementation on balance in Parkinson's disease: does age matter? PLoS One 13(9):e0203637</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30256811</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6157857</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Hong CT, Huang YH, Liu HY, Chiou HY, Chan L, Chien LN (2016) Newly diagnosed Anemia increases risk of Parkinson's disease: a population-based cohort study. Sci Rep 6:29651</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27412825</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4944159</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Hou L, Li Q, Jiang L, Qiu H, Geng C, Hong JS, Li H, Wang Q (2018) Hypertension and diagnosis of Parkinson's disease: a meta-analysis of cohort studies. Front Neurol 9:162</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29615961</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5867351</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Huan Y, Cohen D, Townsend R (2015) Pathophysiology of hypertension in chronic kidney disease. In: Kimmel PL, and Rosenberg ME chronic renal disease. Elsevier Inc, London, pp. 163–169</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Hughes KC, Gao X, Kim IY, Rimm EB, Wang M, Weisskopf MG, Schwarzschild MA, Ascherio A (2016) Intake of antioxidant vitamins and risk of Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord 31(12):1909–1914</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27787934</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5154924</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Jackson P, Loughrey CM, Lightbody JH et al (1995) Effect of hemodialysis on total antioxidant capacity and serum antioxidants in patients with chronic renal failure. Clin Chem 41:1135–1138</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7628087</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Jain A, Migdalska A, Jain A (2014) Endothelin-1-induced endoplasmic reticulum stress in Parkinson's disease. Pharmacologia 5(3):84–90</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Jang W, Park J, Shin KJ, Kim JS, Kim JS, Youn J, Cho JW, Oh E, Ahn JY, Oh KW, Kim HT (2014) Safety and efficacy of recombinant human erythropoietin treatment of non-motor symptoms in Parkinson's disease. J Neurol Sci 337(1–2):47–54</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24289887</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Jin X, Liu MY, Zhang DF, Gao H, Wei MJ (2018) Elevated circulating magnesium levels in patients with Parkinson's disease: a meta-analysis. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat 14:3159–3168</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30510425</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6250112</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Joglar B, Rodriguez-Pallares J, Rodriguez-Perez AI, Rey P, Guerra MJ, Labandeira-Garcia JL (2009) The inflammatory response in the MPTP model of Parkinson's disease is mediated by brain angiotensin: relevance to progression of the disease. J Neurochem 109(2):656–669</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19245663</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Jones G (2007) Expanding role for vitamin D in chronic kidney disease: importance of blood 25-OH-D levels and extra-renal 1alpha-hydroxylase in the classical and nonclassical actions of 1alpha,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3). Semin Dial 20(4):316–324</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17635821</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kao M, Ang D, Pall A, Struthers A (2009) Oxidative stress in renal dysfunction: mechanisms, clinical sequelae and therapeutic options. J Hum Hypertens 24(1):1–8</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kasten M, Tadic V, Klein C, Rocca WA, Savica R, Eric Ahlskog J, Grossardt BR (2010) Anemia or low hemoglobin levels preceding Parkinson disease: a case-control study. Neurology 74(20):1655–1656</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479367</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kisic B, Miric D, Dragojevic I et al (2016) Role of myeloperoxidase in patients with chronic kidney disease. Oxidative Med Cell Longev 2016:1069743</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Klein IH, Ligtenberg G, Neumann J, Oey PL, Koomans HA, Blankestijn PJ (2003) Sympathetic nerve activity is inappropriately increased in chronic renal disease. J Am Soc Nephrol 14:3239–3244</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14638922</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Knekt P, Kilkkinen A, Rissanen H et al (2010) Serum vitamin D and the risk of Parkinson disease. Arch Neurol 67(7):808–811</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20625085</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3091074</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kohan DE (2010) Endothelin, hypertension and chronic kidney disease: new insights. Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens 19(2):134–139</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20051851</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2912219</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Krassilnikova M, Ostrow K, Bader A et al (2014) Low dietary intake of vitamin D and vitamin D deficiency in hemodialysis patients. J Nephrol Ther 4(3):166</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25068077</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4109326</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kuchta A, Pacanis A, Kortas-Stempak B, Çwiklińska A, Ziętkiewicz M, Renke M, Rutkowski B (2011) Estimation of oxidative stress markers in chronic kidney disease. Kidney Blood Press Res 34(1):12–19</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21071957</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kucuk M, Kaya M, Kalayci R, Cimen V, Kudat H, Arican N, Elmas I, Korkut F (2002) Effects of losartan on the blood-brain barrier permeability in long-term nitric oxide blockade-induced hypertensive rats. Life Sci 71(8):937–946</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12084390</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Laudisio A, Lo Monaco MR, Silveri MC, Bentivoglio AR, Vetrano DL, Pisciotta MS, Brandi V, Bernabei R, Zuccalà G (2017) Use of ACE-inhibitors and falls in patients with Parkinson's disease. Gait Posture 54:39–44</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28258036</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Lee A, Gilbert RM (2016) Epidemiology of Parkinson disease. Neurol Clin 34(8):955–965</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27720003</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Lee PH, Shin DH, Kim JW, Song YS, Kim HS (2006) Parkinsonism with basal ganglia lesions in a patient with uremia: evidence of vasogenic edema. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 12:93–96</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16256408</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Li YC (2010) Renoprotective effects of vitamin D analogs. Kidney Int 78(2):134–139</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19471320</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Li YC, Kong J, Wei M, Chen ZF, Liu SQ, Cao LP (2002) 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D(3) is a negative endocrine regulator of the renin-angiotensin system. J Clin Invest 110(2):229–238</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12122115</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">151055</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Liakopoulos V, Roumeliotis S, Gorny X et al (2017) Oxidative stress in hemodialysis patients: a review of the literature. Oxidative Med Cell Longev 2017:1–22</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Liang T, Qian Z, Mu M et al (2020) Brain hepcidin suppresses major pathologies in experimental parkinsonism. iScience 23(7):101284</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32623334</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">7334576</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Lin H, Lin H, Chen Y (2012) Increased risks of parkinsonism in the 3 years after chronic renal failure. Int J Clin Pract 66(5):499–503</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22452548</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Ling X, Kuo K (2018) Oxidative stress in chronic kidney disease. Ren Replace Ther 4(1)</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Luo X, Ou R, Dutta R, Tian Y, Xiong H, Shang H (2018) Association between serum vitamin D levels and Parkinson's disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol 9:909</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30483205</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6240665</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Mallappallil M, Friedman EA, Delano BG, McFarlane SI, Salifu MO (2014) Chronic kidney disease in the elderly: evaluation and management. Clin Pract (Lond) 11(5):525–535</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Manrique C, Lastra G, Gardner M, Sowers JR (2009) The renin angiotensin aldosterone system in hypertension: roles of insulin resistance and oxidative stress. Med Clin North Am 93(3):569–582</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19427492</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2828938</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Mao CJ, Zhong CK, Yang Y, Yang YP, Wang F, Chen J, Zhang JR, Zhang HJ, Jin H, Xu LL, Huang JY, Liu CF (2017) Serum sodium and chloride are inversely associated with dyskinesia in Parkinson's disease patients. Brain Behav 7(12):e00867</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29299386</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5745246</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Mariani S, Ventriglia M, Simonelli I, Donno S, Bucossi S, Vernieri F, Melgari JM, Pasqualetti P, Rossini PM, Squitti R (2013) Fe and cu do not differ in Parkinson's disease: a replication study plus meta-analysis. Neurobiol Aging 34(2):632–633</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22738721</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Martin WR, Wieler M, Gee M (2008) Midbrain iron content in early Parkinson disease: a potential biomarker of disease status. Neurology 70:1411–1417</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18172063</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Martin-Bastida A, Ward RJ, Newbould R, Piccini P, Sharp D, Kabba C, Patel MC, Spino M, Connelly J, Tricta F, Crichton RR, Dexter DT (2017) Brain iron chelation by deferiprone in a phase 2 randomised double-blinded placebo controlled clinical trial in Parkinson's disease. Sci Rep 7(1):1398</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469157</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">28469157</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Massano J, Bhatia KP (2012) Clinical approach to Parkinson's disease: features, diagnosis, and principles of management. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med 2(6):a008870</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22675666</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3367535</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Massy ZA, Ceballos I, Chadefaux-Vekemens B, Nguyen-Khoa T, Descamps-Latscha B, Drüeke TB, Jungers P (2001) Homocyst(e)ine, oxidative stress, and endothelium function in uremic patients. Kidney Int Suppl 78:S243–S245</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11169019</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Mazumder MK, Giri A, Kumar S, Borah A (2016) A highly reproducible mice model of chronic kidney disease: evidences of behavioural abnormalities and blood-brain barrier disruption. Life Sci 161:27–36</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27493078</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Mazumder MK, Paul R, Bhattacharya P et al (2019) Neurological sequel of chronic kidney disease: from diminished Acetylcholinesterase activity to mitochondrial dysfunctions, oxidative stress and inflammation in mice brain. Sci Rep 9:3097</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30816118</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6395638</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>McGonigle RJ, Wallin JD, Shadduck RK, Fisher JW (1984) Erythropoietin deficiency and inhibition of erythropoiesis in renal insufficiency. Kidney Int 25(2):437–444</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6727139</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Medeiros MS, Schumacher-Schuh A, Cardoso AM, Bochi GV, Baldissarelli J, Kegler A, Santana D, Chaves CMMBS, Schetinger MRC, Moresco RN, Rieder CRM, Fighera MR (2016) Iron and oxidative stress in Parkinson's disease: an observational study of injury biomarkers. PLoS One 11(1):e0146129</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26751079</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4709097</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Michaud J, Naud J, Ouimet D, Demers C, Petit JL, Leblond FA, Bonnardeaux A, Gascon-Barré M, Pichette V (2010) Reduced hepatic synthesis of calcidiol in uremia. J Am Soc Nephrol 21(9):1488–1497</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20595682</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3013518</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Modlinger P, Wilcox C, Aslam S (2004) Nitric oxide, oxidative stress, and progression of chronic renal failure. Semin Nephrol 24(4):354–365</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15252775</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Mullapudi A, Gudala K, Boya CS, Bansal D (2016) Risk of Parkinson's disease in the users of antihypertensive agents: an evidence from the meta-analysis of observational studies. J Neurodegener Dis 2016:5780809</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27516917</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4969534</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Nam G, Kim N, Han K et al (2019) Chronic renal dysfunction, proteinuria, and risk of Parkinson's disease in the elderly. Mov Disord 34(8):1184–1191</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31021467</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Negida A, Menshawy A, El Ashal G et al (2016) Coenzyme Q10 for patients with Parkinson's disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets 15(1):45–53</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553164</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Nemeth E, Tuttle MS, Powelson J, Vaughn MB, Donovan A, Ward DM, Ganz T, Kaplan J (2004) Hepcidin regulates cellular iron efflux by binding to ferroportin and inducing its internalization. Science 306(5704):2090–2093</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15514116</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Núñez MT, Urrutia P, Mena N, Aguirre P, Tapia V, Salazar J (2012) Iron toxicity in neurodegeneration. Biometals 25(4):761–776</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318507</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Nussbaum RL, Ellis CE (2003) Alzheimer’s disease and Parkinson’s disease. N Engl J Med 348(14):356–1364</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Ori Y, Bergman M, Bessler H, Zingerman B, Levy-Drummer RS, Gafter U, Salman H (2013)</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Parkinson Study Group STEADY-PD III Investigators (2020) Isradipine versus placebo in early Parkinson disease: a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med 172(9):591–598</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Pedroso I, Bringas ML, Aguiar A, Morales L, Alvarez M, Valdés PA, Alvarez L (2012) Use of Cuban recombinant human erythropoietin in Parkinson's disease treatment. MEDICC Rev 14(1):11–17</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22334107</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Pedroso I, Garcia M, Casabona E, Morales L, Bringas M, Pérez L, Rodríguez T, Sosa I, Ricardo Y, Padrón A, Amaro D (2018) Protective activity of Erythropoyetine in the cognition of patients with Parkinson's disease. Behav Sci (Basel) 8(5):51</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Pelisch N, Hosomi N, Ueno M, Nakano D, Hitomi H, Mogi M, Shimada K, Kobori H, Horiuchi M, Sakamoto H, Matsumoto M, Kohno M, Nishiyama A (2011) Blockade of AT1 receptors protects the blood-brain barrier and improves cognition in Dahl salt-sensitive hypertensive rats. Am J Hypertens 24(3):362–368</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21164491</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Peuchant E, Carbonneau MA, Dubourg L, Thomas MJ, Perromat A, Vallot C, Clerc M (1994) Lipoperoxidation in plasma and red blood cells of patients undergoing haemodialysis: vitamins A, E, and iron status. Free Radic Biol Med 16(3):339–346</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8063197</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Pitts TO, Piraino BH, Mitro R et al (1998) Hyperparathyroidism and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D deficiency in mild, moderate, and severe renal failure. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 67(5):876–881</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Qiu C, Hu G, Kivipelto M, Laatikainen T, Antikainen R, Fratiglioni L, Jousilahti P, Tuomilehto J (2011) Association of blood pressure and hypertension with the risk of Parkinson disease: the national FINRISK study. Hypertension 57(6):1094–1100</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21536985</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Rama Rao KV, Jayakumar AR, Norenberg DM (2003) Ammonia neurotoxicity: role of the mitochondrial permeability transition. Metab Brain Dis 18(2):113–127</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12822830</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Reardon KA, Mendelsohn FA, Chai SY, Horne MK (2000) The angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitor, perindopril, modifies the clinical features of Parkinson's disease. Aust NZ J Med 30(1):48–53</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Rey P, Lopez-Real A, Sanchez-Iglesias S, Muñoz A, Soto-Otero R, Labandeira-Garcia JL (2007) Angiotensin type-1-receptor antagonists reduce 6-hydroxydopamine toxicity for dopaminergic neurons. Neurobiol Aging 28:555–567</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16621167</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Rimmelzwaan LM, van Schoor NM, Lips P et al (2016) Systematic review of the relationship between vitamin D and Parkinson's disease. J Parkinsons Dis 6(1):29–37</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26756741</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4927872</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Roderick PJ, Atkins RJ, Smeeth L, Mylne A, Nitsch DDM, Hubbard RB, Bulpitt CJ, Fletcher AE (2009) CKD and mortality risk in older people: a community-based population study in the United Kingdom. Am J Kidney Dis 53:950–960</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19394727</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Rodriguez-Pallares J, Rey P, Parga JA, Muñoz A, Guerra MJ, Labandeira-Garcia JL (2008) Brain angiotensin enhances dopaminergic cell death via microglial activation and NADPH-derived ROS. Neurobiol Dis 31(1):58–73</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18499466</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Rozani V, Giladi N, Gurevich T, el-Ad B, Tsamir J, Hemo B, Peretz C (2019) Anemia in men and increased Parkinson's disease risk: a population-based large scale cohort study. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 64:90–96</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30922776</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Sanchez B, Relova J, Gallego R et al (2009) 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3administration to 6-hydroxydopamine-lesioned rats increases glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor and partially restores tyrosine hydroxylase expression in substantia nigra and striatum. J Neurosci Res 87(3):723–732</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18816795</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Schapira AH (2008) Mitochondria in the aetiology and pathogenesis of Parkinson's disease. Lancet Neurol 7(1):97–109</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18093566</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Seshiah PN, Weber DS, Rocic P et al (2002) Angiotensin II stimulation of NAD(P)H oxidase activity: upstream mediators. Circ Res 91(5):406–413</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12215489</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Sheu YL, Cheng SJ, Chen YM et al (2007) The syndrome of bilateral basal ganglia lesions in diabetic uremic patients presenting with a relapsing and remitting course: a case report. Acta Neurol Taiwanica 16:226–230</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Shulman JM, De Jager PL, Feany MB (2011) Parkinson’s disease: genetics and pathogenesis. Annu Rev Pathol 6:193–222</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21034221</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Sim JJ, Shi J, Calara F, Rasgon S, Jacobsen S, Kalantar-Zadeh K (2011) Association of plasma renin activity and aldosterone-renin ratio with prevalence of chronic kidney disease: the Kaiser Permanente Southern California cohort. J Hypertens 29(11):2226–2235</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21941205</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Sleeman I, Aspray T, Lawson R, Coleman S, Duncan G, Khoo TK, Schoenmakers I, Rochester L, Burn D, Yarnall A (2017) The role of vitamin D in disease progression in early Parkinson's disease. J Parkinsons Dis 7(4):669–675</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28984616</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5676984</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Soliman RH, Oraby MI, Hussein M, Abd el-Shafy S, Mostafa S (2019) Could vitamin D deficiency have an impact on motor and cognitive function in Parkinson’s disease? Egypt J Neurol Psychiatry Neurosurg 55:34</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Stauffer ME, Fan T (2014) Prevalence of anemia in chronic kidney disease in the United States. PLoS One 9(1):e84943</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24392162</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3879360</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Sung CC, Hsu YC, Chen CC et al (2013) Oxidative stress and nucleic acid oxidation in patients with chronic kidney disease. Oxidative Med Cell Longev 2013:301982</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Surace MJ, Block ML (2012) Targeting microglia-mediated neurotoxicity: the potential of NOX2 inhibitors. Cell Mol Life Sci 69(14):2409–2427</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22581365</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3677079</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Suzuki M, Yoshioka M, Hashimoto M, Murakami M, Noya M, Takahashi D, Urashima M (2013) Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of vitamin D supplementation in Parkinson disease. Am J Clin Nutr 97(5):1004–1013</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23485413</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Suzuki N, Yamamoto M (2016) Roles of renal erythropoietin-producing (REP) cells in the maintenance of systemic oxygen homeostasis. Pflugers Arch 468(1):3–12</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26452589</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Takeda A, Nyssen OP, Syed A, Jansen E, Bueno-de-Mesquita B, Gallo V (2014) Vitamin a and carotenoids and the risk of Parkinson's disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neuroepidemiology 42(1):25–38</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24356061</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Takemoto F, Shinki T, Yokoyama K, Inokami T, Hara S, Yamada A, Kurokawa K, Uchida S (2003) Gene expression of vitamin D hydroxylase and megalin in the remnant kidney of nephrectomized rats. Kidney Int 64(2):414–420</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12846736</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Tedla FM, Brar A, Browne R, Brown C (2011) Hypertension in chronic kidney disease: navigating the evidence. Int J Hypertens 2011:132405</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747971</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3124254</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Tolosa E, Wenning G, Poewe W (2006) The diagnosis of Parkinson’s disease. Lancet Neurol 5:75–86</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16361025</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Townsend K, Evans KN, Campbell MJ, Colston KW, Adams JS, Hewison M (2005) Biological actions of extra-renal 25-hydroxyvitamin D-1α-hydroxylase and implications for chemoprevention and treatment. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol 97:103–109</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081283</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Tsukamoto T, Kitano Y, Kuno S (2013) Blood pressure fluctuation and hypertension in patients with Parkinson’s disease. Brain Behav 3(6):710–714</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24363973</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3868175</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Tumur Z, Shimizu H, Enomoto A, Miyazaki H, Niwa T (2010) Indoxyl sulfate upregulates expression of ICAM-1 and MCP-1 by oxidative stress-induced NF-κB activation. Am J Nephrol 31(5):435–441</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20389059</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Tysnes O, Storstein A (2017) Epidemiology of Parkinson's disease. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 124(8):901–905</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>United States Renal Data System. 2019 USRDS Annual Data Report: Epidemiology of Kidney Disease in the United States, National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases. Bethesda, MD, 2019</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Vaziri ND, Dicus M, Ho N et al (2003) Oxidative stress and dysregulation of superoxide dismutase and NADPH oxidase in renal insufficiency. Kidney Int 63(1):179–185</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12472781</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Vaziri ND (2004) Oxidative stress in uremia: nature, mechanisms, and potential consequences. Semin Nephrol 24(5):469–473</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15490413</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Vaziri ND, Oveisi F, Ding Y (1998) Role of increased oxygen free radical activity in the pathogenesis of uremic hypertension. Kidney Int 53:1748–1754</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9607208</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Vela D (2018) The dual role of Hepcidin in brain Iron load and inflammation. Front Neurosci 12:740</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30374287</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6196657</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Voormolen N, Grootendorst DC, Urlings TA et al (2010) Prevalence of Anemia and its impact on mortality and hospitalization rate in Predialysis patients. Nephron Clin Pract 115:133–141</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wang HC, Brown P, Lees AJ (1998) Acute movement disorders with bilateral basal ganglia lesions in uremia. Mov Disord 13:952–957</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9827621</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wang HC, Cheng SJ (2003) The syndrome of acute bilateral basal ganglia lesions in diabetic uremic patients. J Neurol 250:948–955</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12928914</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wang I, Lin C, Wu Y et al (2014) Increased risk of Parkinson's disease in patients with end-stage renal disease: a retrospective cohort study. Neuroepidemiology 42(4):204–210</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24751820</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wang S, Yun J, Shin D et al (2017) Chronic kidney disease: a risk factor for Parkinson’s disease. Korean J Clin Geriatr 18(2):95–101</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Weidmann P, Maxwell MH, Lupu AN, Lewin AJ, Massry SG (1971) Plasma renin activity and blood pressure in terminal renal failure. N Engl J Med 285(14):757–762</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5567260</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wesson DE, Buysse JM, Bushinsky DA (2020) Mechanisms of metabolic acidosis-induced kidney injury in chronic kidney disease. J Am Soc Nephrol 31(3):469–482</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31988269</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Williams DR, Litvan I (2013) Parkinsonian syndromes. Continuum (Minneap Minn) 19(5 movement disorders):1189-1212</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wirdefeldt K, Adami HO, Cole P et al (2011) Epidemiology and etiology of Parkinson’s disease: a review of the evidence. Eur J Epidemiol 26(Suppl 1):S1–S58</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21626386</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wright JW, Harding JW (2011) Brain renin-angiotensin--a new look at an old system. Prog Neurobiol 95(1):49–67</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21777652</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wright JW, Harding JW (2013) The brain renin-angiotensin system: a diversity of functions and implications for CNS diseases. Pflugers Arch 465(1):133–151</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22535332</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Xu Q, Kanthasamy AG, Jin H, Reddy MB (2016) Hepcidin plays a key role in 6-OHDA induced Iron overload and apoptotic cell death in a cell culture model of Parkinson's disease. Parkinsons Dis 2016:8684130</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27298749</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4889865</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Yang F, Wolk A, Håkansson N, Pedersen NL, Wirdefeldt K (2017) Dietary antioxidants and risk of Parkinson's disease in two population-based cohorts. Mov Disord 32(11):1631–1636</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28881039</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5698752</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Yu XP, Bellido T, Manolagas SC (1995) Down-regulation of NF-kappa B protein levels in activated human lymphocytes by 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 92(24):10990–10994</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7479923</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">40556</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Yue X, Li H, Yan H, Zhang P, Chang L, Li T (2016) Risk of Parkinson disease in diabetes mellitus. Medicine 95(18):e3549</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27149468</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4863785</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Zahed NS, Chehrazi S (2017) The evaluation of the relationship between serum levels of Interleukin-6 and Interleukin-10 and metabolic acidosis in hemodialysis patients. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl 28(1):23–29</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28098099</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Zaritsky J, Young B, Wang HJ, Westerman M, Olbina G, Nemeth E, Ganz T, Rivera S, Nissenson AR, Salusky IB (2009) Hepcidin--a potential novel biomarker for iron status in chronic kidney disease. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 4(6):1051–1056</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19406957</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2689881</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Zechel S, Huber-Wittmer K, von Bohlen und Halbach O (2006) Distribution of the iron-regulating protein hepcidin in the murine central nervous system. J Neurosci Res 84(4):790–800</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16933319</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Zhang CY, He FF, Su H, Zhang C, Meng XF (2020) Association between chronic kidney disease and Alzheimer's disease: an update [published online ahead of print, 2020 Apr 3]. Metab Brain Dis 35:883–894. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11011-020-00561-y</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11011-020-00561-y</ArticleId>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32246323</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Zhang M, Mao Y, Ramirez SH et al (2010) Angiotensin II induced cerebral microvascular inflammation and increased blood-brain barrier permeability via oxidative stress. Neuroscience 171(3):852–858</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20870012</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Zhang Z, Sun L, Wang Y, Ning G, Minto AW, Kong J, Quigg RJ, Li YC (2008) Renoprotective role of the vitamin D receptor in diabetic nephropathy. Kidney Int 73(2):163–171</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17928826</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Zhang Z, Yuan W, Sun L, Szeto FL, Wong KE, Li X, Kong J, Li YC (2007) 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 targeting of NF-kappaB suppresses high glucose-induced MCP-1 expression in mesangial cells. Kidney Int 72(2):193–201</Citation>
                <ArticleIdList>
                    <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507908</ArticleId>
                </ArticleIdList>
            </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>